[Music]
Welcome to busy central lounge edition
2025 release wave 2. In this session I
will show you new feature in
sustainability and this is enable to
measure all gases as a carbon
equivalent.
It can help a lot in lot specific
situations. So let's switch to explain
business values. It can simplify access
to emission factors. How actually what
is about? Very often you cannot find
emission factors for each of gases. For
example, you can find for carbon but not
for metan. Uh some of producer of
emission factors or publishers they will
publish all this information but not so
often. So there is a very often
situation you want to deliver carbon
equivalent for metan carbon equivalent
for nitrium for other gases. So this is
common and this is something what I got
as a feedback from many partners. So now
we will simplify this access to emission
factors because we are asking if you set
up this way only for carbo equivalent.
So it will simplify emission factors it
is simplified data entry and
standardized emission reporting. So it
will be much easier for carbo equivalent
values. So how it works because now
depends how you will set up. You have
two options. Um if you want to use
previous model where you wanted to use
all emissions uh as accurate emissions
fac emissions for each of gases this is
something what we already had in the
system you just need to continue to use
this way. So you will have for all of
them you need to enter accurate
emissions per each of gas for when
posting. So in sustainability journal or
in a purchase documents. So everywhere
you need to enter for each of gases
accurate information. But if you set up
and if you want to use uh all
information as a carbon dioxide
equivalent for all gas emissions, you
need to go to sustainability setup and
to enable carbon equivalence for all
gases. And from this moment you will see
uh we will have a changes in all your
pages. So all your page will show
different uh captions for emissions.
Earlier for example you can find metan
so
default emission for CH4. Now it will be
written carbon equivalent for uh CH4. So
this is what you will get everywhere
will be different. We will get
automatically pre set up emissions fees
based on uh this new approach and this
is what you will see. So you in all
documents in sustainability journals in
purchase documents, sustainability
ledger entries even on items on
resources everywhere you will see new
caption and you need to enter only
carbon equivalents for these gases. So
let's make a look. This is before enable
setup. So you will see on it card we
have default carbon deoxided default
metan and other gases. So all of them
are regular and you need to enter
accurate emission. So if you switch to
purchase again the same default CO2
default CH4 so all default emissions
even when we go to um ledger entries
again the same information. But now once
when we switch to sustainability setup
you can see this new field use all
emissions as a carboard equivalent and
when we enable it from this moment we
will have different captions and it
assume that you will enter different
information. So now when I look into
item cards you will see that this is
default carbon equivalent for carbon
dioxide default carbon equivalent for
metan. If you again go back to the same
purchasing voice. Yes. Now new captures
default carbon equivalent for all these
gases. What else? We got automatically
configured in a background because we
have these emission fees where we
already had um a carbon equivalent
factor for all these gases. But now as
we are using carbon equivalent for all
of them, all of them will be set up as a
one because this is default value. But
if you do not use it, you need to use
different carbon equivalent for all of
these gases. So this is everything about
this functionality on the first side.
Very small but very useful information
based on how you track your gas
emissions.
So before I close this session, I would
like to remind you to check all these
general B center resources. Interesting
information you can learn a lot. Then do
not forget to subscribe on LinkedIn
channel where you can find weekly uh
news uh additional announcements from uh
our team and watch more videos on
YouTube only for sustainability. We have
uh seven or eight videos for this uh
edition but you can find for many
additional functionalities in this
edition and previous edition. So go
there akamsbc YouTube
and thank you for watching this session.